<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>dcSpark Blog Blog</title>
        <link>https://blog.dcspark.io/</link>
        <description>dcSpark Blog Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[dcSpark Catalyst Fund 10 Grant Proposals]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.dcspark.io/fund10-grant-proposals</link>
            <guid>https://blog.dcspark.io/fund10-grant-proposals</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Cover image]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="Cover image" src="/assets/images/cover2-9e93a072cb210527d352197dab935e76.png" width="1100" height="619" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Time has come for Catalyst fund 10, and we have proposals for new core infrastructure we think is both unique and will help pave a path for future success of the Cardano ecosystem.</p><p>dcSpark has been one of the most reliable companies for completing Catalyst grant proposals. Despite dcSpark only account for only about 1% of all proposals, we represent about 5~10% of all completed proposals - demonstrating our ability to deliver on our promises</p><p>True to our goal of being ecosystem builders, we have contributed to many things from core infrastructure, sidechains, open-source smart contracts, specifications and user-facing products. This time, however, we've decided to put all our efforts into <b><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qlaXTJObDJk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">autonomous worlds</a></b>, onchain gaming and gamification</p><p>Notably, we believe that through <a href="https://twitter.com/paimastudios" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Paima Engine</a>, we have the ability to build the most competitive platform in all of crypto and be the global leader in one of the fastest growing segments in Web3.</p><p>However, if you've looked more into Paima (such as in our <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HtvemijxF-0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Youtube explained</a>), you'll notice that although Paima is building in the Cardano ecosystem, that the technology can (and inevitably will) be used on different chains as well. We're big believers in aligning incentives, and so we want to make sure that the success of Paima also means the success of everybody who has supported the team on the journey.</p><p>To explain how we plan to align incentives, first we have to talk about the business model of Paima: it is similar to a game engine. That is to say, it's free to use, but using Paima for commercial purposes and crossing a revenue threshold means you have to pay. The long-term goal is to DAOify Paima in the future. Although the exact fee system may change over time, our proposal is to <strong>give a discount to any project using Paima to deploy their app in the Cardano ecosystem</strong>. That is to say, if for example you have to pay a 7% royalty for revenue crossing the threshold when deploying your game to Ethereum, you would only (for example) have to pay 3.5% when deploying in the Cardano ecosystem. To put it more formally, Paima will reduce any costs for projects deploying in Cardano up to 50% pro-rated depending on how many of our proposals pass. If 100% of our proposals pass, the reduction will be 50%. If only ½ of our proposals pass, the reduction will only be 25%.</p><p>We believe this system will strongly align the two ecosystems together. It allows us to very easily pitch Cardano as the best ecosystem for projects planning to use Paima, not just thanks to the lower royalty costs, but also thanks to the fact that Paima will support Cardano NFTs which are generally much safer to work with than ERC721 tokens while being secured by one of the most decentralized blockchains. We hope you're as excited about the potential of Autonomous Worlds and Paima as we are, and look forward to building a strong ecosystem, together.</p><h1>Core</h1><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="core-integrations-to-support-the-fast-growing-onchain-games-and-autonomous-world-segment">Core integrations to support the fast-growing onchain games and autonomous world segment<a href="#core-integrations-to-support-the-fast-growing-onchain-games-and-autonomous-world-segment" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Core integrations to support the fast-growing onchain games and autonomous world segment" title="Direct link to Core integrations to support the fast-growing onchain games and autonomous world segment">​</a></h3><p>Cost: ~130K USD</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Proposal summary</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><div>This proposal is the combination of thee separate tasks<ul><li>Shinkai Visor AI LLM to allow onchain games to leverage decentralized AI components - 40k <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1F8q_7m3MEvuSwCICTc81HGmB-tgeEROrfIJUqBG6GIg/edit" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></li><li>Virtual Wallets so users don't need a crypto wallet installed to play, and potentially just play with something like Apple FaceID - 60k <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/15TqBvMJl9TqIA2MEjYvG2KLkOx5Sbviqn_tPAfyVQ3s/edit" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></li><li>Social login for Paima (Google login, Microsoft account, etc.) - 30k <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1R1JIkrNksR-T-ETbGXkLpQhdsdKcmTA7YxQ345BNynI/edit#heading=h.pv6x4u8av1dp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></li></ul></div></div></div></details><p>Ideascale: <a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/107591" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a><br>
Lidonation: <a href="https://www.lidonation.com/proposals/core-integrations-to-support-the-fast-growing-onchain-games-and-autonomous-world-segment-f10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="allow-using-nfts-from-cardano-and-other-ecosystem-in-onchain-games-hosted-in-the-cardano-ecosystem">Allow using NFTs from Cardano and other ecosystem in onchain games hosted in the Cardano ecosystem<a href="#allow-using-nfts-from-cardano-and-other-ecosystem-in-onchain-games-hosted-in-the-cardano-ecosystem" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Allow using NFTs from Cardano and other ecosystem in onchain games hosted in the Cardano ecosystem" title="Direct link to Allow using NFTs from Cardano and other ecosystem in onchain games hosted in the Cardano ecosystem">​</a></h3><p>Cost: ~145K USD</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Proposal summary</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><div>This proposal is composed of 3 different components to be able to reference 3 different kinds of NFTs from Paima:<p>Paima Projection NFTs - 145k</p><ul><li>Paima Projection NFT Whirlpool continued work for Cardano 75k <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1nEz9fe8UqkSvFJ-nSYwuvOrrcnPIO853znUK2VCDvxE/edit" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></li><li>Paima Projection NFT Whirlpool for EVM 40k <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1cv95BmdpgMbh43MR1ewH_YM5utc4uh1y773dT73ezro/edit" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></li><li>Paima Projection NFT Whirlpool for Polkadot WASM NFTs 30k <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1m4iJM9PNMuewPJUeixRK8BrWmMGnXhb18VYiIyAoH7U/edit" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></li></ul><br>Each proposal increases the viability of Paima by allowing games deployed to the Cardano ecosystem to leverage the liquidity of an increasing number of NFT ecosystems, as well as allow Cardano NFTs to be used in games hosted in other ecosystems<br><br>You can see the individual proposals for more details, but generally if you want to learn about the architecture for this system at a deeper technical level, we’ve written an Aiken smart contract for Cardano which has extensive documentation that you can find [here](https://github.com/dcSpark/projected-nft-whirlpool/)</div></div></div></details><p>Ideascale: <a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/107656" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a><br>
Lidonation: <a href="https://www.lidonation.com/proposals/allow-using-nfts-from-cardano-and-other-ecosystem-in-onchain-games-hosted-in-the-cardano-ecosystem-f10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="enable-use-cases-that-require-frequent-message-signing-by-introducing-a-safe-standard-for-message-signing-without-wallet-prompts">Enable use-cases that require frequent message signing by introducing a safe standard for message signing without wallet prompts<a href="#enable-use-cases-that-require-frequent-message-signing-by-introducing-a-safe-standard-for-message-signing-without-wallet-prompts" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Enable use-cases that require frequent message signing by introducing a safe standard for message signing without wallet prompts" title="Direct link to Enable use-cases that require frequent message signing by introducing a safe standard for message signing without wallet prompts">​</a></h3><p>Cost: ~40K USD</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Proposal summary</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><div>There has been a lot of growth in use-cases that require frequent message signing in the crypto ecosystem - primarily driven by NFTs and gaming. However, a lot of users lose interest when they realize how tedious it will be to accept the prompt by their wallet every time they have to sign a message<br><br><p>As the authors of original Cardano message signing spec (CIP8: <a href="https://cips.cardano.org/cips/cip8/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://cips.cardano.org/cips/cip8/</a>), we are very familiar with the cryptography involved in message signing. We are planning to release a layer on top of this message signing system to more easily allow wallets to auto-sign messages in cases where it knows it is safe to do so. Although we will create a more formal specification, you can find the initial approaches discussed in the following document: <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1VqXjyfgvbXxYHqhzYcSFFEorYbnza6GbjyAbVXyAKAM/edit?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a><br><br></p><p>Notably, a lot of the power of this proposal will rely on Paima Engine - a framework for creating web3 games, as it supports playing games using only standard message signing (no real transaction required). That means that if we have a safe and smooth flow for message signing, we can unlock a significantly better gaming experience.<br><br></p><p>Notably, the project consisted of the steps:</p><ol><li>Create a specification for this message signing system</li><li>Integrate it into at least one wallet</li></ol></div></div></div></details><p>Ideascale: <a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/107668" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a><br>
Lidonation: <a href="https://www.lidonation.com/proposals/enable-use-cases-that-require-frequent-message-signing-by-introducing-a-safe-standard-for-message-signing-without-wallet-prompts-f10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="paima-integration-of-frontend-game-engines--novel-technology">Paima integration of Frontend Game Engines &amp; Novel Technology<a href="#paima-integration-of-frontend-game-engines--novel-technology" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Paima integration of Frontend Game Engines &amp; Novel Technology" title="Direct link to Paima integration of Frontend Game Engines &amp; Novel Technology">​</a></h3><p>Cost: ~160K USD</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Proposal summary</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><div><p>Currently there are integrations of Cardano wallets (through Paima) into multiple systems engines like:</p><ul><li>Unity</li><li>Phaser</li><li>Game Maker</li><li>Javascript</li><li>LLM AI models</li></ul><p>Some of these integrations can be found <a href="https://github.com/PaimaStudios/paima-game-templates" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a><br><br></p><p>However, we plan to add integrations to the following systems as well:</p><ul><li>Unreal Engine</li><li>GPS connections</li><li>iOS and Android</li><li>AR device if possible (like Vision Pro)<br><br></li></ul><p>Since new engines occasionally appear, we will monitor the space to other opportunities as well and reserve the right to change our mind about which engine/platform we prioritize spending funds on to maximize impact</p></div></div></div></details><p>Ideascale: <a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/107684" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a><br>
Lidonation: <a href="https://www.lidonation.com/proposals/paima-onchain-game-integration-of-frontend-game-engines-novel-technology-f10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="enable-apps-and-games-that-require-large-amounts-of-data-to-function-cheaply-while-still-maximizing-availability-and-safety">Enable apps and games that require large amounts of data to function cheaply while still maximizing availability and safety<a href="#enable-apps-and-games-that-require-large-amounts-of-data-to-function-cheaply-while-still-maximizing-availability-and-safety" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Enable apps and games that require large amounts of data to function cheaply while still maximizing availability and safety" title="Direct link to Enable apps and games that require large amounts of data to function cheaply while still maximizing availability and safety">​</a></h3><p>Cost: ~60K USD</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Proposal summary</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><div>Currently, many growing fields in the blockchain space sometimes require kilobytes of data per transaction to work. Notably, zk cryptography, L2s and web3 gaming<br><br><p>Since these L2s and web3 gaming are both fairly high-frequency use-cases (transactions happen often), solutions like IPFS are not well equipped to store and pin all the different files. A common solution to this is to use a “Data Availability Layer” (DA Layer) such as Celestia or Avail that is optimized for these kinds of use-cases. However, using a DA Layer comes with a disadvantage because you have to trust the DA layer to function properly, and is generally more expensive and slower than posting the data directly to the underlying L1<br><br></p><p>To tackle this problem in Paima, we propose allowing games and apps using Paima to use “Volitions”, which try to get the best of both worlds. They allow users to choose in which case they post their data directly on the L1, and in which case they post their data on the DA Layer. This allows clients to optimize for the best experience<br><br></p><p>Notably, we plan to integrate Avail Project (<a href="https://www.availproject.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.availproject.org/</a>) first as we believe they have the highest synergy with the Cardano ecosystem: they are based on Polkadot (whose underlying consensus is inspired by Ouroboros), and they have invested in a research-based approach working with new primitives like Coded Merkel Trees (<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=thdxHtQgszk" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a>) to make their technology competitive<br><br></p><p>Notably, the plan for integration will have the following steps:</p><ul><li>Enable Paima to follow both the settlement layer and the DA light client at the same time</li><li>Allow a way for clients to choose whether or not data gets posted to the settlement layer or the DA layer</li><li>Allow merging L1 and DA layer data into a single stream for Paima apps to handle</li></ul></div></div></div></details><p>Ideascale: <a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/107691" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a><br>
Lidonation: <a href="https://www.lidonation.com/proposals/enable-apps-and-games-that-require-large-amounts-of-data-to-function-cheaply-while-still-maximizing-availability-and-safety-f10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="enable-apps-and-games-built-in-the-cardano-ecosystem-to-leverage-zk-cryptography-for-privacy-and-scalability">Enable apps and games built in the Cardano ecosystem to leverage ZK cryptography for privacy and scalability<a href="#enable-apps-and-games-built-in-the-cardano-ecosystem-to-leverage-zk-cryptography-for-privacy-and-scalability" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Enable apps and games built in the Cardano ecosystem to leverage ZK cryptography for privacy and scalability" title="Direct link to Enable apps and games built in the Cardano ecosystem to leverage ZK cryptography for privacy and scalability">​</a></h3><p>Cost: ~100K USD</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Proposal summary</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><div>Currently many companies are looking into blockchain adoption for use-cases like commemorative NFTs point systems, DID, traceability and more. However, all of these require private data to avoid GDPR violations, which make them hard to manage with open systems like blockchains. Similarly, a lot of decentralized games are interested in similar concepts as they allow building games with information asymmetry like fog-of-war which is an important game mechanic. Additionally, the verifiability of ZK proofs also means that these could eventually be used to cheaply implement DeFi-focused components to games written with Paima (things that resemble casinos)<br><br><p>Currently there is no good way to build these use-cases in the Cardano ecosystem, but fortunately Paima Engine (a framework for creating web3 apps and games) has a fairly clear path to adding these primitives. Notably, as a L2 solution, it has a lot more flexibility in adding new cryptographic primitives which are always hard to add directly to the Cardano L1<br><br></p><p>Paima Engine allows writing onchain apps with Javascript, making them fairly easy to write for all developers. For the ZK circuit component, we’ve decided to partner with ZekoLabs. The reason is because they also allow writing ZK circuits in Javascript (so it feels like a unified experience for developers), and their system is based on Mina which is also compatible with Ouroboros and so it is a friendly project towards the Cardano community<br><br></p><p>Notably, the plan for integration will have the following steps:</p><ul><li>Allow running ZK proofs locally and associating their results to Stateful NFTs. </li><li>Allow monitoring ZK appchains and merging their state into a Paima app</li></ul></div></div></div></details><p>Ideascale: <a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/107706" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a><br>
Lidonation: <a href="https://www.lidonation.com/proposals/enable-apps-and-games-built-in-the-cardano-ecosystem-to-leverage-zk-cryptography-for-privacy-and-scalability-f10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="support-stateful-nfts-dynamic-nfts-for-gaming-in-nft-marketplaces">Support Stateful NFTs (dynamic NFTs) for gaming in NFT marketplaces<a href="#support-stateful-nfts-dynamic-nfts-for-gaming-in-nft-marketplaces" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Support Stateful NFTs (dynamic NFTs) for gaming in NFT marketplaces" title="Direct link to Support Stateful NFTs (dynamic NFTs) for gaming in NFT marketplaces">​</a></h3><p>Cost: ~100K USD</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Proposal summary</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><div>Stateful NFTs can be really complex. For example, the image for your NFT could be the result of a complex aggregation of multiple events on chain and heavy computation. This means that building a NFT marketplace that renders all Stateful NFTs perfectly is a hard problem<br><br><p>Instead, our goal will be to create a system so that games and apps can easily and cheaply setup app-specific NFT marketplaces that render their NFTs as desired. To avoid this having a negative impact on the liquidity of the NFT, we will build it in such a way that using this system means your NFT can still appear on other NFT marketplace (albeit maybe without being able to render the information in the NFT in as rich of a way)<br><br></p><p>We also want to build a browser extension that helps render Stateful NFT information on existing marketplaces so that users can still get the full stateful information without having to resort to hunt down a lot of app-specific marketplaces</p></div></div></div></details><p>Ideascale: <a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/103520" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a><br>
Lidonation: <a href="https://www.lidonation.com/proposals/support-stateful-nfts-dynamic-nfts-for-gaming-in-nft-marketplaces-f10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></p><h1>Extended</h1><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="open-source-poap-in-cardano">Open Source POAP in Cardano<a href="#open-source-poap-in-cardano" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Open Source POAP in Cardano" title="Direct link to Open Source POAP in Cardano">​</a></h3><p>Cost: ~80K USD</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Proposal summary</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><div>Proof of Attendance Protocol (POAP) is a protocol that uses blockchain technology to create badges or collectibles to mark the attendance at an event. It is proven to be of great adoption in the majority of the EVM compatible blockchains, with more than 6.5M POAPs already minted. Believe it or not, this is only 2M less than the ENTIRE NFT ecosystem in Cardano!<br><br><p>More concretely, users would receive a single Stateful Proof of Attendance NFT (SPOAP NFT) that starts out blank, and every time they participate in an event, they would get a new commemorative NFT embedded inside their SPoA. If they've ever received a single SPoA in their entire lifetime, event organizers will not have to mint them a new one which means the more users participate in the protocol, the cheaper it will get to distribute NFTs.<br><br></p><p>Additionally, to enable building soulbound NFTs, these NFTs will be minted on Milkomeda (Cardano sidechain). This has the added benefit that transaction fees are also significantly cheaper than the Cardano L1, allowing for much larger and more regular drops and also bypasses the min UTxO issue. Thanks to the Milkomeda's work on wrapped smart contracts, it's still possible for Cardano users to fully control their SPoA directly from any Cardano wallet (Nami/Eternl/Flint/etc) and will not require any new wallets to be installed for neither event organizers nor regular participants</p></div></div></div></details><p>Ideascale: <a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/100932/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a><br>
Lidonation: <a href="https://www.lidonation.com/proposals/open-source-poap-in-cardano-f10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="extend-nft-sale--drop-tools-to-support-dropping-more-complex-assets-as-required-for-onchain-games">Extend NFT sale &amp; drop tools to support dropping more complex assets as required for onchain games<a href="#extend-nft-sale--drop-tools-to-support-dropping-more-complex-assets-as-required-for-onchain-games" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Extend NFT sale &amp; drop tools to support dropping more complex assets as required for onchain games" title="Direct link to Extend NFT sale &amp; drop tools to support dropping more complex assets as required for onchain games">​</a></h3><p>Cost: ~115K USD</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Proposal summary</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><div>If we look at funding platforms like Kickstarter, there are often multiple tiers to each preorder with (often overlapping) rewards. Trying to handle all this complexity at the NFT sale tool level is not only extremely complicated, it often introduces regulatory issues as most NFT sale platforms do not support purchasing fungible tokens for regulatory reasons.<br><br><p>To solve this, we will leverage Stateful NFTs created by Paima Engine. Notably, Stateful NFTs are NFTs that can evolve overtime based on user actions. We will use this to allow purchasing into preorders to receive a Stateful NFT which can later be redeemed in-game once the game is launched. This allows very flexible pre-order systems as the redemption logic and tokens do not have to be created at the time of sale (similar to Kickstarter)<br><br></p><p>Notably, the user flow will look at follows:</p><ul><li>User finds a game doing a pre-order on an NFT platform that they want to participate in</li><li>They pay with ADA (or any other tokens the site supports) to buy into the pre-order, which uses Milkomeda wrapped smart contracts to credit them a Stateful NFT</li><li>(optional) if they choose to add more money into the pre-order, their existing Stateful NFT will be updated</li><li>Once the sale is over, use their Stateful NFT to claim their in-game reward once the game is release</li></ul><p>We may work with Plutus Art for the first implementation, but we reserve the right to change partners depending on factors such as their availability</p></div></div></div></details><p>Ideascale: <a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/107533" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a><br>
Lidonation: <a href="https://www.lidonation.com/proposals/extend-nft-sale-drop-tools-to-support-dropping-more-complex-assets-as-required-for-onchain-games-f10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="open-standard-for-cross-game-achievement-system-to-gamify-onchain-participation">Open standard for cross-game achievement system to gamify onchain participation<a href="#open-standard-for-cross-game-achievement-system-to-gamify-onchain-participation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Open standard for cross-game achievement system to gamify onchain participation" title="Direct link to Open standard for cross-game achievement system to gamify onchain participation">​</a></h3><p>Cost: ~75K USD</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Proposal summary</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><div>The goal of an open standard for cross-game achievements should be that any website or app can choose to support the achievement system without having to rely on any central server, as opposed to existing achievement systems that are depend on a central party like XBox Live or PlayStation<br><br><p>To create an open cross-chain achievement standard we have a few requirements:</p><ul><li>Achievements for a game can have in-game effects (ex: a game can unlock an in-game area if you have 5+ achievements unlocked). However, achievements in one game need not be accessible from another</li><li>Services need to be able to efficiently read all achievements for a user’s account across games without having to rely on a centralized server</li><li>Companies can self-specify achievements for their game without having to register with a central server</li></ul><br>The main implementer of this system will be Paima Engine - a framework for creating onchain games and autonomous worlds.<br><br><p>Notably, it will work by:</p><ul><li>Defining a standard interface for client indexers written for Paima that games need to implement</li><li>The achievement website will scan all games written with Paima using the RPC standard to find the static data about which achievements are available in the game and which stateful NFTs are used for the game</li><li>The achievement website will scan the user’s wallet for all addresses they own, and check if they own any NFT related to any Paima games. If so, it will query the games through the RPC standard to find which achievements they’ve unlocked and display them</li></ul><br>To bring this to life, we will implement this standard, create an example achievement website that leverages it, and implement it into 3 games (Jungle Wars, Wrath of the Jungle, Tarochi)</div></div></div></details><p>Ideascale: <a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/107558" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a><br>
Lidonation: <a href="https://www.lidonation.com/proposals/open-standard-for-cross-game-achievement-system-to-gamify-onchain-participation-f10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="allow-cardano-users-to-call-sidechain-smart-contracts-directly-from-their-cardano-mainnet-wallet">Allow Cardano users to call Sidechain smart contracts directly from their Cardano mainnet wallet<a href="#allow-cardano-users-to-call-sidechain-smart-contracts-directly-from-their-cardano-mainnet-wallet" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Allow Cardano users to call Sidechain smart contracts directly from their Cardano mainnet wallet" title="Direct link to Allow Cardano users to call Sidechain smart contracts directly from their Cardano mainnet wallet">​</a></h3><p>Cost: ~100K USD</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Proposal summary</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><div>Sidechains have always been part of Cardano’s scaling model, with some sidechains already existing like Milkomeda (EVM sidechain) and more planned. Additionally, L2s are increasing in popularity in other ecosystems and Cardano as well through Paima, which also help scale and add flexibility to the ecosystem.<br><br><p>However, it’s hard to get adoption for new sidechains or L2s if users have to download a new specific wallet for every sidechain and L2 they interact with. Having wallet developers do native integrations also just does not scale (only 24hrs in a day and they probably have other Cardano features they want to focus on).<br><br></p><p>To tackle this, we’ve developed a system called Wrapped Smart Contracts that allows users to call Milkomeda smart contracts directly from Cardano wallets (Nami, Eternl, Flint and more) without any extra work on behalf of the wallet developers.<br><br></p><p>You can find more information at <a href="https://docs.milkomeda.com/category/wrapped-smart-contracts" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://docs.milkomeda.com/category/wrapped-smart-contracts</a><br><br></p><p>The project is (at time of writing) undergoing final integration by partner dApps before officially going live.<br><br></p><p>Notably, the project consisted of the steps:</p><ul><li>Writing the specifications</li><li>Integrating the system inside the EVM itself on Milkomeda (precompiles)</li><li>Integrating the systems inside the Milkomeda bridge</li><li>Coordinate a hardfork of Milkomeda to introduce these upgrades</li><li>Having partners integrate Wrapped Smart Contracts into their dApps</li></ul></div></div></div></details><p>Ideascale: <a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/107634" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a><br>
Lidonation: <a href="https://www.lidonation.com/proposals/allow-cardano-users-to-call-sidechain-smart-contracts-directly-from-their-cardano-mainnet-wallet-f10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="mlabs--cardano-game-engine-wallet---godot-integration">MLabs – Cardano Game Engine Wallet - Godot Integration<a href="#mlabs--cardano-game-engine-wallet---godot-integration" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to MLabs – Cardano Game Engine Wallet - Godot Integration" title="Direct link to MLabs – Cardano Game Engine Wallet - Godot Integration">​</a></h3><p>Cost: ~115K USD</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Proposal summary</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><div>Godot is an engine, with the following benefits:<ul><li>It is open-source, which greatly simplifies the work needed to quickly get wallet support up and running</li><li>Godot is quickly gaining significant adoption, particularly among indie developers (who, we believe, are the most likely to develop innovative blockchain integrations and experiment with new designs and revenue models)</li><li>There are no licensing requirements or fees attached to its usage - which makes it attractive even to large game studios. (We note that Godot has recently been used by a major studio to develop a Sonic game, which demonstrates that it is suitable for both small-scale and large-scale development)</li><li>Supports a robust system for extending the core engine (GDExtension), which promises to make the development of Cardano integration tools relatively painless.</li></ul><br>We plan to provide an easy way to integrate Cardano wallets into games written with Godot, as well as Paima integration in general</div></div></div></details><p>Ideascale: <a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/100468" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a><br>
Lidonation: <a href="https://www.lidonation.com/proposals/mlabs-cardano-game-engine-wallet-godot-integration-f10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="powering-onchain-game-functionality-using-cardano-stakepools">Powering onchain game functionality using Cardano stakepools<a href="#powering-onchain-game-functionality-using-cardano-stakepools" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Powering onchain game functionality using Cardano stakepools" title="Direct link to Powering onchain game functionality using Cardano stakepools">​</a></h3><p>Cost: ~200K USD</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Proposal summary</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><div>Currently there is a high inherent financial incentive for high monitoring of DeFi-related applications and so there is a relatively easy path to decentralize the infrastructure related to dApp operation.<br><br><p>For gaming, autonomous world and metaverse applications however, even if the infrastructure is made to be decentralizable, it’s hard to convince others to run the infrastructure as it is purely a selfless act for the greater good. To tackle this, we want to enable Cardano stake pools to be able to run infrastructure for onchain games and, through a connection to the Cardano L1, be able to know which player is delegating to their pool and support them by, for example, reducing or covering entirely the transaction fees for their in-game actions<br><br></p><p>An interesting point of this proposal is that this infrastructure would not only allow Cardano stake pool to provide this kind of benefit to users playing games written with Paima in the Cardano ecosystem, but more generally would be able to provide these kinds of services for users across the crypto landscape, giving non-Cardano projects an easy path to leverage Cardano infrastructure to secure their game as well as introducing non-Cardano users to the Cardano ecosystem in case they want to purchase and delegate ADA to take advantage of benefits<br><br></p><p>Notably, the plan for integration will have the following steps:</p><ul><li>Create an indexer using Scrolls or Carp to get pool information in the right format needed for Paima</li><li>Provide better customizability of the Paima infrastructure (notably the batcher system) so that pools can easily modify its configuration to choose which benefits they want to provide without having to know how to code</li><li>Integrate the indexer built in step (1) into the customization system from step (2) so that pools can lookup who is delegating to them to activate the benefits</li><li>Add a way for stake pools to register themselves for games so that users know they can leverage their infrastructure either through a registry infrastructure or an on-chain registration</li></ul></div></div></div></details><p>Ideascale: <a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/107742" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a><br>
Lidonation: <a href="https://www.lidonation.com/proposals/powering-onchain-game-functionality-using-cardano-stakepools-f10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="provide-multiple-templates-on-how-to-write-apps-and-games-for-the-cardano-ecosystem-using-paima">Provide multiple templates on how to write apps and games for the Cardano ecosystem using Paima<a href="#provide-multiple-templates-on-how-to-write-apps-and-games-for-the-cardano-ecosystem-using-paima" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Provide multiple templates on how to write apps and games for the Cardano ecosystem using Paima" title="Direct link to Provide multiple templates on how to write apps and games for the Cardano ecosystem using Paima">​</a></h3><p>Cost: ~100K USD</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Proposal summary</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><div><p>Paima Engine is a framework for building gamification and gaming use-cases for blockchains. It already comes with multiple templates such as board games, onchain ai, card games, rpg game and more that can be found <a href="https://github.com/PaimaStudios/paima-game-templates" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a><br><br></p><p>We want to build even more templates, especially around gamification use-cases such as</p><ul><li>Point systems where users gain points for real-life actions (such as purchasing a drink)</li><li>Traceability where the state of an object updates </li><li>Games &amp; apps of different genre</li></ul><br>We do not commit to any specific template as there is quite a lot to pick from, and we want to avoid committing to specific templates that others may have already built by the time Catalyst ends.</div></div></div></details><p>Ideascale: <a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/107713" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a><br>
Lidonation: <a href="https://www.lidonation.com/proposals/provide-multiple-templates-on-how-to-write-apps-and-games-for-the-cardano-ecosystem-using-paima-f10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></p><h1>Supplement</h1><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="shinkai-visor-cardano-indexer-integration-vector-db">Shinkai Visor Cardano Indexer integration (vector DB)<a href="#shinkai-visor-cardano-indexer-integration-vector-db" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Shinkai Visor Cardano Indexer integration (vector DB)" title="Direct link to Shinkai Visor Cardano Indexer integration (vector DB)">​</a></h3><p>Cost: ~40K USD</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Proposal summary</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><div><p>We will create a specialized connector to integrate with Shinkai Visor, a tool developed to interact with websites and other applications. This connector will be able to leverage Cardano's data and convert it into vector embeddings that can be used by Large Language Models (LLMs) to perform effective querying. The connector will be able to process data about transactions, DEX prices, and other valuable information present on the Cardano blockchain.</p></div></div></div></details><p>Ideascale: <a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/106716" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a><br>
Lidonation: <a href="https://www.lidonation.com/proposals/shinkai-visor-cardano-indexer-integration-vector-db-f10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="exhibit-largest-blockchain-expojpcardano-is-hardly-recognized-in-japan-therefore-we-will-exhibit-at-one-of-the-largest-trade-shows-to-raise-awareness-and-encourage-developers-to-enter-the-market">Exhibit Largest Blockchain EXPO(JP)：Cardano is hardly recognized in Japan. Therefore, we will exhibit at one of the largest trade shows to raise awareness and encourage developers to enter the market.<a href="#exhibit-largest-blockchain-expojpcardano-is-hardly-recognized-in-japan-therefore-we-will-exhibit-at-one-of-the-largest-trade-shows-to-raise-awareness-and-encourage-developers-to-enter-the-market" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Exhibit Largest Blockchain EXPO(JP)：Cardano is hardly recognized in Japan. Therefore, we will exhibit at one of the largest trade shows to raise awareness and encourage developers to enter the market." title="Direct link to Exhibit Largest Blockchain EXPO(JP)：Cardano is hardly recognized in Japan. Therefore, we will exhibit at one of the largest trade shows to raise awareness and encourage developers to enter the market.">​</a></h3><p>Cost: ~95K USD</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Proposal summary</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><div><p>Japan has come to be a leader in Web3 during the bear market with the Japanese government promoting Web3 adoption. We have been extremely active in Japan attending many events with booths and speakers. This proposal will help continue to fund and scale these activities</p></div></div></div></details><p>Ideascale: <a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/103058" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a><br>
Lidonation: <a href="https://www.lidonation.com/proposals/exhibit-largest-blockchain-expojpcardano-is-hardly-recognized-in-japan-therefore-we-will-exhibit-at-one-of-the-largest-trade-shows-to-raise-awareness--f10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="unlocking-a-multi-million-dollar-nfcnft-authentication-market-for-the-cardano-ecosystem-with-open-source">Unlocking a Multi-million Dollar NFC/NFT Authentication Market for the Cardano Ecosystem with Open-Source<a href="#unlocking-a-multi-million-dollar-nfcnft-authentication-market-for-the-cardano-ecosystem-with-open-source" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Unlocking a Multi-million Dollar NFC/NFT Authentication Market for the Cardano Ecosystem with Open-Source" title="Direct link to Unlocking a Multi-million Dollar NFC/NFT Authentication Market for the Cardano Ecosystem with Open-Source">​</a></h3><p>Cost: ~30K USD</p><details class="details_lb9f alert alert--info details_b_Ee" data-collapsed="true"><summary>Proposal summary</summary><div><div class="collapsibleContent_i85q"><div><p>We’ll create an open-source proof-of-concept application, a mobile SDK to communicate and generate an NFC hardware wallet and validate NFT ownership with the wallet created for both Cardano as well as Paima in general</p></div></div></div></details><p>Ideascale: <a href="https://cardano.ideascale.com/c/idea/106026" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a><br>
Lidonation: <a href="https://www.lidonation.com/proposals/fixing-nintendos-problem-unlocking-a-multi-million-dollar-nfcnft-authentication-market-for-the-cardano-ecosystem-with-open-source-cardano-warriors-dcs-f10" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">link</a></p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="conclusion">Conclusion<a href="#conclusion" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Conclusion" title="Direct link to Conclusion">​</a></h2><p><strong>Follow dcSpark:</strong> <br>
<strong>Website:</strong> <a href="https://dcspark.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">dcspark.io</a><br>
<strong>Twitter:</strong> <a href="https://twitter.com/dcspark_io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@dcSpark</a><br>
<strong>Discord:</strong> <a href="https://discord.gg/dcspark" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Invite</a><br>
<strong>YouTube:</strong> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@dcSpark" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">dcSpark</a><br></p><p><strong>Follow Paima:</strong> <br>
<strong>Website:</strong> <a href="https://paimastudios.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">paimastudios.com</a><br>
<strong>Twitter:</strong> <a href="https://twitter.com/PaimaStudios" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@PaimaStudios</a><br>
<strong>Discord:</strong> <a href="https://discord.com/invite/jZ59ArVaxv" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Invite</a><br>
<strong>YouTube:</strong> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCiQQPg--xxGnFXDfMmot4AA" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Paima Studios</a><br></p><p><strong>Follow Shinkai:</strong> <br>
<strong>Twitter:</strong> <a href="https://twitter.com/shinkai_network" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@ShinkaiNetwork</a><br>
<strong>Discord:</strong> <a href="https://discord.com/invite/shinkainetwork" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Invite</a><br></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>catalyst</category>
            <category>cardano</category>
            <category>paima</category>
            <category>shinkai</category>
            <category>milkomeda</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>